<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-25T05:46:58+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Rucha Pendharkar</title><author><name>Rucha Pendharkar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Yankee Doodle Diary</title><link href="/2024/05/15/yankee-doodle-diary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yankee Doodle Diary" /><published>2024-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2024/05/15/yankee-doodle-diary</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/05/15/yankee-doodle-diary.html"><![CDATA[<p>With the arrival of spring after my first winter in Boston, my friends and I found a new hobby; day trips to the New England shore. Despite being a stone’s throw away from Boston, each promises a unique experience.</p>

<hr />

<h2> Newport, Rhode Island </h2>

<p>A trip to the Ocean State made me realize why the Northeast America is called <em>New England</em>.</p>

<p>We started our visit with the State House in Providence. This is a must see for any history geek! The different board rooms are open to public for viewing, but they also have some cool artifacts from the civil war. One highlight was the old canon they used in the Battle of Gettysburg.</p>

<p>While Providence was like any other modern day New England city (not as many Dunkins as Massachusetts though), Newport will transport you back to Colonial times. The city of Newport is also referred to as the <em>summer playground of the American barons of industry</em> and I could see why. With small brightly colored houses, European style churches and clock towers, this coastal city exudes charm. We visited Newport in early spring and were blessed with views of cherry blossoms and tulips. The wharf is known for outstanding seafood, and fun ocean themed restaurants. Despite not indulging in the seafood myself, I have to admit that the old oil-lamps, elevated bar stools and rustic furniture, anchors and chains everywhere perfectly recreates the experience of having lunch inside a ship like <em>the Pirates of the Caribbean!</em></p>

<p>It took us forty minutes, but we walked across the city to visit Easton’s Beach. Along the way we saw beautiful homes and small vintage shops selling the odd knick-knacks. Easton’s beach was beautiful, with views of a stormy grey Atlantic. Our main destination, however was Cliff Walk. This walking trail has views of the ocean on your left, and century old, gorgeous mansions on your right, as you walk along a rocky cliff. Most of these mansions were rumoured to be owned by big time celebrities and pop-stars. The trail forks off at places, allowing you to descend closer to the ocean. The sound of the waves crashing into the rocks is loud, but oddly calming. The highlight of this trail is the Breaker’s Mansion, the grandest of all the homes. While it was closed when we visited, the aesthetics will remind you of a scene from <em>Bridgerton</em></p>

<p>We ended the day with a trip to the Beavertail Lighthouse at sunset. This is the third oldest lighthouse in all of America. It offers you unbridled views of the ocean. Legend has it that continuing in a straight line from this point would lead one all the way to Europe. It also has a small museum which talks about the role of this lighthouse in the World Wars. There’s a bunch of rocks you can sit on, closer to the water and watch the sun touch the water. A perfect way to end the day.</p>

<hr />

<h2> Plum Island, Massachusetts</h2>
<p>Just along the border of New Hampshire and Massachusetts, lies the idyllic town of Gloucester. This is further up north from the famous Manchester-by-the-Sea. We visited Stage Fort Park which overlooked Cape Ann. The daises were in full bloom in the August heat. It was our lucky day - after exploring around a bit more, we stumbled on a town fair, and a vintage car show. My, oh my was that a treat! Brightly colored Mustangs, Corvette Sting Rays, Fords and so many more cars gleaming in the sun. I’m not that knowledgeable about cars, but I was excited nevertheless. I miss the pastel pop of color cars had, before all of them turned vanilla monochrome with a few odd reds and blues. Grumpy old Americans trying to stop strangers from touching their vintage cars, while nibbling on one of the most atrocious snacks I have seen in my life - deep fried Oreo’s. Gloucester truly captures <em>the Spirit of America</em></p>

<p>After lunch we decided to head to Plum Island to laze around on the beach. The beach was quiet, and not too crowded. The water was a deep blue, perfectly reflecting the sky. It was warm where the sun shone, and cold in the shadows. We didn’t do much except laze around, talk, play football, and make holes in the sand. Plum Island also has a private airfield, right next to the beach. We headed to Newburyport after, for some ice-cream. It had a small downtown, with quaint shops. There was a small harbour with a lot of private yachts; I assume the assets of the uber wealthy residents of <em>Beantown</em>. I am a firm believer that local ice-cream parlors make better ice cream than big brand chains. And I was right, the ice cream was extremely delicious.</p>

<p>And while it was annoying to get the sand out of my shoes (and the car), I could not have thought of a better way to spend a sunny summer Saturday.</p>

<hr />

<h2> Portland, Maine </h2>

<p>As you cross over the state border, a sign reads <em>“Welcome to Maine: The Way Life Should Be”</em>. There’s a faint trace of salt in the air, and you begin to spot seagulls in the sky. The trees grew taller, straight and denser. I’ve always been partial to views of forests, ocean and mountains together. On a warm spring day, this feels extremely pleasant. This <em>is</em> how life should be.</p>

<p>Our first stop was a local bakery chain - The Holy Donut. Donuts don’t particularly excite me anymore (side effects of having too many Dunkins in Massachusetts), this one however is worth the visit. Made entirely out of potato, instead of wheat or flour, these gluten-free donuts were probably the best I’ve had in my life. They were dense, yet extremely soft with a variety of toppings and fillings. Definitely worth a visit!</p>

<p>Exploring downtown Portland revealed a quaint yet charming cityscape, with scattered buildings surrounding a picturesque park. We made our way to the Eastern Promenade Trail. This is a scenic walking trail along the Casco Bay. The water touches the sky, in an endless stretch of blue in front of you. There were a few kids picnicking and people were lazing on the lawns. A section of the trail branches off to a small beach. The views are spectacular, and if you are lucky you might run into some playful dogs here.</p>

<p>After rolling around in the grass and taking in some much needed sun, we went to another local chain for lunch. Otto’s Pizza. I’d had Otto’s Pizza in Boston before, but I was excited to try the original in Portland. It did not disappoint. They had a bunch of different toppings - pineapples, roasted eggplants, and probably the weirdest - mashed potato. For a town with a reputation for lobster rolls, the potato seemed to be making it’s way into a lot of their food. I wonder what that is about.</p>

<p>We spent the afternoon visiting the Bug Lighthouse and the surrounding park in South Portland. People were flying kites and there were a lot of older grandparents out for an afternoon stroll. This was a small lighthouse, which was supposed to be inspired by a monument in Athens. The wharf and docks were the busiest part of the city. However everything closes down as soon as the clock strikes 5pm. We ended the day with our final stop -the famous Portland Headlight. This is Maine’s oldest lighthouse, overlooking the wondrous Cape Elizabeth. Built with white stone, with red sloping roofs and white picket fence, this lighthouse will remind you of a scene from a quintessential European town. The golden hour just made it even more stunning.</p>

<hr />

<p>Whether it’s the bustling harbor of Newport, the sandy shores of Plum Island, or the serene Promenade, one tradition remains steadfast; no trip is complete without a lively round of Monopoly Deal on the sun-kissed grass (or sand). Oblivious to the amused looks, we trade properties and lose most of our money, while we try to stop our cards from flying away in the cool ocean breeze.</p>

<h2>Fin</h2>]]></content><author><name>Rucha Pendharkar</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the arrival of spring after my first winter in Boston, my friends and I found a new hobby; day trips to the New England shore. Despite being a stone’s throw away from Boston, each promises a unique experience.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Guide to Outsmarting Your Uninvited Roommates</title><link href="/2024/04/05/a-guide-to-outsmarting-your-uninvited-roomates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Guide to Outsmarting Your Uninvited Roommates" /><published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2024/04/05/a-guide-to-outsmarting-your-uninvited-roomates</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/04/05/a-guide-to-outsmarting-your-uninvited-roomates.html"><![CDATA[<p>Living in certain Boston neighborhoods, such as Mission Hill, Fenway, Park Drive or Brookline, often comes with a guaranteed encounter with a common foe – the mouse. This piece compiles practical advice gathered from personal experiences, insights and the internet (reddit), aiming to guide you through the challenges of dealing with these pesky creatures.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>If you ever think you’ve spotted a mouse, trust your instincts – you probably did. Don’t let your roommates gaslight you into thinking you’re seeing things. Trust me, they’ll have their own mouse showdown sooner or later. And if your roommates scream <em>“Mouse!”</em> believe them and spring into action!</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Resist the temptation to give your mouse a name. Sure, Mickey sounds adorable, and Jerry is cute but remember, we’re talking about your sworn enemy here. Humanizing the foe won’t make the battle any easier – keep your mindset sharp.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Mouse traps never trap anything. As a beginner, you might be tempted to try the innocent (and cheap) glue trap, wanting to release the mouse into a forest or a park. You might think, I don’t want to kill him for no reason. Don’t be a fool. The innocent-looking glue trap may seem like a humane choice, but it’s more likely to catch dust than mice.</p>

    <p>Enter the classic transparent cage, a seemingly ingenious contraption. Picture a long, hollow tube with a few air holes and a clever trap door. Here’s the catch (pun intended): bait needs to be strategically placed at both ends. Once our unsuspecting mouse ventures inside for a snack, it triggers the trap door, effectively sealing the entrance. Sounds foolproof, right? Not quite. Mice aren’t fond of elaborate dining experiences; they’d rather snatch the food off the door and dash away. Sometimes, the trap may deploy due to a subtle vibration from the refrigerator or dishwasher, leaving you with a false alarm.</p>

    <p>Next we have the popular and classic snap mouse trap, popularly seen in Tom &amp; Jerry. This trap is more harmful to humans than to rodents. There’s a greater chance of hurting one of your fingers than catching a mouse. Do not use this, especially if you are clumsy (like me) and have no experienced people around you.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Mice adore corners and dark crevices, especially around kitchens. Use traps strategically to block these sneaky entry and exit points. And remember, mice are surprisingly good jumpers, so don’t underestimate their acrobatic skills when blocking entrances!</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Don’t waste time building a maze to guide Jerry out. He will climb over it and not respect your efforts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Don’t panic and call your dad. He will ask you to get a cat.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Spraying essential oils around entrances might make your apartment smell delightful, but Jerry couldn’t care less.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Playing cat sounds does not work. You’ll only feel sad that you never had a pet cat (Thanks Mom), and we don’t want to go down that spiral.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Unlike dogs, treating your mouse like a pet i.e calling out his name fondly (if you ignore advice (2)), will not cause him to come running out to meet you. They do get zoomies though. Asking him to leave nicely (saying things like please, thank you) also do not work.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Your male friends are equally scared of mice. They will offer stupid suggestions like <em>keep some cheese out for him</em>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Throw out cardboard boxes or anything mice can chew through. Do clean your kitchen every night before sleeping.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Speak to your family and friends. Sometimes this war gets emotionally and mentally exhausting.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Mice love peanut butter, more than cheese! But don’t put it out every day. Knowing that there is peanut butter waiting for them every night makes them visit your home even more. I wasted eight days putting peanut butter on the traps, only to find the food gone and the trap intact the next morning. At that point I felt Jerry was having fun with me.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Seal the gaps between your room doors and the floor. There’s a sticky foam-plastic tape available on Amazon for $8. Stick it to the bottom of your doors. As an added bonus it also helps soundproof the room. Make sure your mouse is localized to only one area of the apartment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reach out to your maintenance team. Pen down your encounters in a descriptive fashion, and send these out to them in a timely manner. Annoy them into coming up with creative solutions. They will always fill up non existent holes in the wall. They may try and delay the pest control, but it’s your right to demand one.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reality check: You will have mice in your apartment even if you have a spotless kitchen. Having a clean kitchen is always better. Do not let the pest control guy, or the maintenance team gaslight you into believing your kitchen is unclean. They will try to blame it on you. So make sure to get important areas checked out, especially the back of the stove and refrigerator.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The entire city of Boston moves in August. And so do mice. Be extra vigilant during the months of August and September.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Always wear closed toe footwear while dealing with them. Mice, especially barn mice, can be really small. A broom is your best friend. If you see a mouse do not be afraid to whack him</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Always remember - They are more scared of you, than you are of them.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>It may seem like I’ll be able to handle my next mouse encounter, but I really won’t. I would not wish this on my worst enemy. So I decided to write this article to put all of this random knowledge I had about mice to good use.</p>

<p>The war (Apartment 1209 vs Jerry) ended on 9th September 2023. After a good month of setting traps, moving furniture around, coaxing him out and trying every trick in the book - my roommate found him lying on the kitchen floor. She whacked him with a broom for good measure, and threw him out the balcony. She can be quite gutsy.</p>

<p>We never knew what worked in the end. All that mattered was the war was over.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rucha Pendharkar</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Living in certain Boston neighborhoods, such as Mission Hill, Fenway, Park Drive or Brookline, often comes with a guaranteed encounter with a common foe – the mouse. This piece compiles practical advice gathered from personal experiences, insights and the internet (reddit), aiming to guide you through the challenges of dealing with these pesky creatures.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adventures in the Big Apple</title><link href="/2023/11/26/adventures-in-the-big-apple.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adventures in the Big Apple" /><published>2023-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/11/26/adventures-in-the-big-apple</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/11/26/adventures-in-the-big-apple.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve never had the quintessential New York tourist experience.</p>

<p>Midnight strolls in Times Square, dollar pizza indulgences, picnics in Central Park, or encounters with giant rodents in the subway are still unchecked on my list; despite having friends in New Jersey who proudly call themselves New Yorkers (akin to Pimpri Chinchwad residents claiming to be Punekars). I'm well aware of the skepticism from genuine locals. But, I digress. My friends persistently rave about the thrill of New York – “Rucha, you never get bored in New York,” “There’s so much to do!” and the classic “The people, Rucha! The people, the energy, and the vibes!” The adrenaline junkie in me was curious, craving an adventure. And boy, adventure did I get.</p>

<p>It was the Sunday after Thanksgiving. I was driving home from Virginia with a couple of friends. We had just spent the week eating, playing board games, lazing around, and eating more - celebrating the true spirit of Thanksgiving. I was supposed to catch a late afternoon bus from the Port Authority back to Boston. We hit traffic when we reached Delaware around noon, and I felt tense. I’ve seen my fair share of traffic living in Boston, Pune, and Bengaluru (a while). My friend was supposed to drop me off at Newark Penn Station, and catching my bus now seemed far-fetched. I wasted time contemplating if I should reschedule my bus to a later time. All of the tickets were sold out. I could not miss work the next day and needed to be home at any cost. I kept refreshing the app in frustration and suddenly saw an open seat on the 6:30 PM bus! I quickly booked it. The bus was from Chinatown, and no one I knew had ever used that service. I’d reach Boston just before midnight. The slight sense of relief I had got, drained away at the thought of explaining these potentially risky travel arrangements to my parents back in India. I called my dad and gave him the necessary details, and I was surprised to see him quite okay with my decision, or maybe he was sleepy and did not fully register what I told him. Either way, I was grateful and felt pretty confident. Now, to reach New York… </p>

<p>For a barely used BMW, the car was moving slowly. Or maybe my friend who drove it could have been better at driving. I kept looking at my watch every five minutes. The Garden State welcomed us with a rainstorm as we entered New Jersey. Cars around us slowed down. My phone’s battery was draining out. I was getting antsy, fidgeting nervously in my seat. It was four in the afternoon, and we were an hour away from the train station. After another hour of anxiety, I reached Penn Station in the pouring rain at a quarter past five. Quick goodbyes, a sprint to the platform for the train to the World Trade Center, and a frantic encounter with a malfunctioning ticket machine ensued. It kept declining my card, and I did not have any petty change on me either. I’ve spent my life running from transit authorities and jumping turnstiles, and for the first time, I wished I would run into a train conductor who would sell me a ticket. Thankfully, a kind old man pointed me to another ticket machine, and I made it onto the train just in time. 
My hands were red from the cold, and my face was flushed. I did a quick mental calculation. Assuming everything goes well -  I would reach the WTC at five minutes past six, which left me five minutes to exit the Occulus and another fifteen minutes to reach the bus terminal. Doable, I thought optimistically. I pre-booked an Uber so that I would not waste any time.</p>

<p>The doors began to close, and a woman screamed. Someone pressed the emergency stop button. I turned around, silently cursing and terrified. The woman was pregnant and was kneeling with her hands on her knees, screaming, “My water broke; someone get me to the hospital!”. People began to panic, and in the middle of her screams of pain, the station emergency services arrived with a wheelchair and whisked her away. It took me a while to comprehend what was going on. Here, I was accounting for minutes to make my bus, and I saw some random woman start to give birth on the New York subway. This was absurd! 
As I pulled into the WTC station, my Uber driver canceled on me and drove away. Probably annoyed that I did not show up in time and cost him a valuable customer. I opened Google Maps, punched in the location, and checked other transportation options. It was a twenty-minute walk - probably a few blocks from the station to the bus terminal. “Well Rucha,” I thought, “looks like you’ll just need to make a run for it.” Frantically, I ran in the middle of the Occulus, entirely unaware to take in my surroundings. I could feel a few snide eyes on me - I am sure the sight of a girl in a slightly oversized jacket, wet hair, and muddy Converse sprinting was not something the Occulus boasted about. </p>

<p>It was thirteen minutes past six, and I exited onto the road and began running in the rain towards the bus. My hands were starting to burn from the cold and friction. My phone was damp; the rain seeped in through the charging port. I ran maybe four blocks and stopped momentarily to catch my breath. Instinctively, I raised my hand to hail a cab, and miraculously, one appeared around the corner! I signaled the driver to open the trunk and yelled, “Take me to 145 Canal Street, please! And hurry! I have to catch a bus in fifteen minutes.” The driver was an old Middle Eastern fellow and told me he would get me there in time. As I pulled out my phone to update my friends on the group chat, the cab came to a halt. “We are here, my dear.” Surprised, I looked up, and there was the bus with people waiting in line to board it! These cabbies and their shortcuts! I thanked him profusely, tipped him generously, and ran to the bus. </p>

<p>It was six thirty on the dot. I ran to the front of the line and asked the driver about my bag. He motioned to stow it in the luggage area at the bottom of the bus. I crouched down, put down my bag, and turned to get out; I was met with an avalanche of luggage as all the other passengers hastily dumped their belongings. I was pushed out of the luggage area from the other side, quite comically. I brushed myself off and suddenly found myself at the front of the line. I had my pick of seats! I found a seat under the heater and dried my hair with a small emergency towel I found in my backpack. 
As I was warming myself up, a tall blonde girl sat next to me. She wore a skirt, tights, sparkly top, and an overcoat with shockingly high and pointy heels - pretty regular for a night on the town, unusual for a four-hour bus ride to Boston. She fished out a mirror and some makeup from her purse and began fixing herself. As she applied mascara, she turned to me and said, “Is this giving slay?” I forced myself not to snort out of laughter and replied, “Yes, it’s giving all sorts of slay.” She humphed. Her idea of warming herself was different. She pulled out a massive bottle of brandy and took a huge sip. A couple more sips, and then she began her story - her fiance cheated on her, and now she is going back to Boston to get revenge. Her story was sad, but it was also peppered with makeup and relationship advice. I am not sure what she meant by revenge, but I would not like to face a sparkly, brandy-drunk, pissed ex-fiancee in high heels. 
I controlled myself not to laugh; those who know me well, know how hard it is for me. Usually, I would have been scared of sitting next to an unusual character such as herself, but I also found it amusing that despite whatever she was going to do, she wanted to make sure her makeup was perfect. Comically absurd. </p>

<p>I spent the remainder of the journey trying to sleep while my neighbor finished off her bottle. I reached home at midnight and collapsed on the couch. To those keeping track, my iPhone survived with 3% of it's battery remaining. Pretty impressive for a day without charging. My roommate was having a late dinner, and that’s when I realized I had not had a bite to eat since noon. I showered, had dinner, and thanked my lucky stars that I was home and dry. </p>

<p>New York is, indeed, quite an experience. There are three pieces of advice I give to you, dear reader -</p>

<ol>
  <li>Embrace cab karma – when in doubt, hail a cab!</li>
  <li>Revenge might be sweet, but it’s even sweeter when your makeup is on point.</li>
  <li>Quoting the great Douglas Adams - A towel is about the most massively useful thing an interstellar hitchhiker can have.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Rucha Pendharkar</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve never had the quintessential New York tourist experience.]]></summary></entry></feed>