<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-03T06:47:19+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Rucha Pendharkar</title><subtitle>Rucha&apos;s Website</subtitle><author><name>Rucha Pendharkar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Adventures in the Big Apple</title><link href="/2023/11/26/adventures-in-the-big-apple.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adventures in the Big Apple" /><published>2023-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/11/26/adventures-in-the-big-apple</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/11/26/adventures-in-the-big-apple.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve never had the quintessential New York tourist experience.</p>

<p>Midnight strolls in Times Square, dollar pizza indulgences, picnics in Central Park, or encounters with giant rodents in the subway are still unchecked on my list; despite having friends in New Jersey who proudly call themselves New Yorkers (akin to Pimpri Chinchwad residents claiming to be Punekars). I'm well aware of the skepticism from genuine locals. But, I digress. My friends persistently rave about the thrill of New York – “Rucha, you never get bored in New York,” “There’s so much to do!” and the classic “The people, Rucha! The people, the energy, and the vibes!” The adrenaline junkie in me was curious, craving an adventure. And boy, adventure did I get.</p>

<p>It was the Sunday after Thanksgiving. I was driving home from Virginia with a couple of friends. We had just spent the week eating, playing board games, lazing around, and eating more - celebrating the true spirit of Thanksgiving. I was supposed to catch a late afternoon bus from the Port Authority back to Boston. We hit traffic when we reached Delaware around noon, and I felt tense. I’ve seen my fair share of traffic living in Boston, Pune, and Bengaluru (a while). My friend was supposed to drop me off at Newark Penn Station, and catching my bus now seemed far-fetched. I wasted time contemplating if I should reschedule my bus to a later time. All of the tickets were sold out. I could not miss work the next day and needed to be home at any cost. I kept refreshing the app in frustration and suddenly saw an open seat on the 6:30 PM bus! I quickly booked it. The bus was from Chinatown, and no one I knew had ever used that service. I’d reach Boston just before midnight. The slight sense of relief I had got, drained away at the thought of explaining these potentially risky travel arrangements to my parents back in India. I called my dad and gave him the necessary details, and I was surprised to see him quite okay with my decision, or maybe he was sleepy and did not fully register what I told him. Either way, I was grateful and felt pretty confident. Now, to reach New York… </p>

<p>For a barely used BMW, the car was moving slowly. Or maybe my friend who drove it could have been better at driving. I kept looking at my watch every five minutes. The Garden State welcomed us with a rainstorm as we entered New Jersey. Cars around us slowed down. My phone’s battery was draining out. I was getting antsy, fidgeting nervously in my seat. It was four in the afternoon, and we were an hour away from the train station. After another hour of anxiety, I reached Penn Station in the pouring rain at a quarter past five. Quick goodbyes, a sprint to the platform for the train to the World Trade Center, and a frantic encounter with a malfunctioning ticket machine ensued. It kept declining my card, and I did not have any petty change on me either. I’ve spent my life running from transit authorities and jumping turnstiles, and for the first time, I wished I would run into a train conductor who would sell me a ticket. Thankfully, a kind old man pointed me to another ticket machine, and I made it onto the train just in time. 
My hands were red from the cold, and my face was flushed. I did a quick mental calculation. Assuming everything goes well -  I would reach the WTC at five minutes past six, which left me five minutes to exit the Occulus and another fifteen minutes to reach the bus terminal. Doable, I thought optimistically. I pre-booked an Uber so that I would not waste any time.</p>

<p>The doors began to close, and a woman screamed. Someone pressed the emergency stop button. I turned around, silently cursing and terrified. The woman was pregnant and was kneeling with her hands on her knees, screaming, “My water broke; someone get me to the hospital!”. People began to panic, and in the middle of her screams of pain, the station emergency services arrived with a wheelchair and whisked her away. It took me a while to comprehend what was going on. Here, I was accounting for minutes to make my bus, and I saw some random woman start to give birth on the New York subway. This was absurd! 
As I pulled into the WTC station, my Uber driver canceled on me and drove away. Probably annoyed that I did not show up in time and cost him a valuable customer. I opened Google Maps, punched in the location, and checked other transportation options. It was a twenty-minute walk - probably a few blocks from the station to the bus terminal. “Well Rucha,” I thought, “looks like you’ll just need to make a run for it.” Frantically, I ran in the middle of the Occulus, entirely unaware to take in my surroundings. I could feel a few snide eyes on me - I am sure the sight of a girl in a slightly oversized jacket, wet hair, and muddy Converse sprinting was not something the Occulus boasted about. </p>

<p>It was thirteen minutes past six, and I exited onto the road and began running in the rain towards the bus. My hands were starting to burn from the cold and friction. My phone was damp; the rain seeped in through the charging port. I ran maybe four blocks and stopped momentarily to catch my breath. Instinctively, I raised my hand to hail a cab, and miraculously, one appeared around the corner! I signaled the driver to open the trunk and yelled, “Take me to 145 Canal Street, please! And hurry! I have to catch a bus in fifteen minutes.” The driver was an old Middle Eastern fellow and told me he would get me there in time. As I pulled out my phone to update my friends on the group chat, the cab came to a halt. “We are here, my dear.” Surprised, I looked up, and there was the bus with people waiting in line to board it! These cabbies and their shortcuts! I thanked him profusely, tipped him generously, and ran to the bus. </p>

<p>It was six thirty on the dot. I ran to the front of the line and asked the driver about my bag. He motioned to stow it in the luggage area at the bottom of the bus. I crouched down, put down my bag, and turned to get out; I was met with an avalanche of luggage as all the other passengers hastily dumped their belongings. I was pushed out of the luggage area from the other side, quite comically. I brushed myself off and suddenly found myself at the front of the line. I had my pick of seats! I found a seat under the heater and dried my hair with a small emergency towel I found in my backpack. 
As I was warming myself up, a tall blonde girl sat next to me. She wore a skirt, tights, sparkly top, and an overcoat with shockingly high and pointy heels - pretty regular for a night on the town, unusual for a four-hour bus ride to Boston. She fished out a mirror and some makeup from her purse and began fixing herself. As she applied mascara, she turned to me and said, “Is this giving slay?” I forced myself not to snort out of laughter and replied, “Yes, it’s giving all sorts of slay.” She humphed. Her idea of warming herself was different. She pulled out a massive bottle of brandy and took a huge sip. A couple more sips, and then she began her story - her fiance cheated on her, and now she is going back to Boston to get revenge. Her story was sad, but it was also peppered with makeup and relationship advice. I am not sure what she meant by revenge, but I would not like to face a sparkly, brandy-drunk, pissed ex-fiancee in high heels. 
I controlled myself not to laugh; those who know me well, know how hard it is for me. Usually, I would have been scared of sitting next to an unusual character such as herself, but I also found it amusing that despite whatever she was going to do, she wanted to make sure her makeup was perfect. Comically absurd. </p>

<p>I spent the remainder of the journey trying to sleep while my neighbor finished off her bottle. I reached home at midnight and collapsed on the couch. To those keeping track, my iPhone survived with 3% of it's battery remaining. Pretty impressive for a day without charging. My roommate was having a late dinner, and that’s when I realized I had not had a bite to eat since noon. I showered, had dinner, and thanked my lucky stars that I was home and dry. </p>

<p>New York is, indeed, quite an experience. There are three pieces of advice I give to you, dear reader -</p>

<ol>
  <li>Embrace cab karma – when in doubt, hail a cab!</li>
  <li>Revenge might be sweet, but it’s even sweeter when your makeup is on point.</li>
  <li>Quoting the great Douglas Adams - A towel is about the most massively useful thing an interstellar hitchhiker can have.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Rucha Pendharkar</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve never had the quintessential New York tourist experience.]]></summary></entry></feed>